In July 2024, a pod of 77 pilot whales washed up on a beach in Orkney, Scotland.
2024年7月，一群由77头领航鲸组成的鲸群在苏格兰奥克尼群岛的一处海滩上搁浅。
It was the largest mass stranding of whales in Scotland for decades.
这是苏格兰几十年来最大规模的鲸鱼集体搁浅事件。
Scientists don't know exactly why whales beach themselves.
科学家们并不确切知道鲸鱼为什么会搁浅。
One theory is that climate change is driving whales' food closer to the shoreline, where they then get stuck as the tide goes out.
一种理论认为，气候变化正将鲸鱼的食物驱赶到离海岸线更近的地方，然后当潮水退去时，它们就会被困在那里。
If a single animal is found, it is usually because it is sick or has been injured.
如果发现的是单只动物，通常是因为它生病或受伤了。
In the Orkney stranding, 12 of the whales were still alive when they became beached.
在奥克尼搁浅事件中，有12头鲸鱼搁浅时仍然活着。
When this happens, marine organisations assess whether a whale can be safely refloated.
当这种情况发生时，海洋组织会评估鲸鱼能否被安全地送回海中。
Professionals and members of the community often come together, cover the animal in wet sheets and pour buckets of water over it, though not the blowhole, until the animal drifts back out to the ocean.
专业人士和社区成员通常会聚集在一起，用湿布盖住鲸鱼，并用水桶往它身上浇水（但不浇呼吸孔），直到动物随潮水漂回大海。
Though it's not always a happy ending.
不过，并不总是圆满结局。
For those that don't survive, a post-mortem examination is often carried out.
对于那些未能存活的鲸鱼，通常会进行尸检。
Dr Brownlow of the Scottish Marine Animal Stranding Scheme told the BBC that these can reveal a lot about the whale's life and the reasons why it was beached.
苏格兰海洋动物搁浅计划的布朗洛博士告诉BBC，这些检查可以揭示出关于鲸鱼生活以及其搁浅原因的很多信息。
In 2024, a very rare species of whale turned up on a beach in New Zealand – a spade-toothed whale.
2024年，一种非常罕见的鲸鱼——铲齿鲸——在新西兰的一处海滩上被发现。
While this is sad, the carcass was dissected in order to help researchers acquire new information about the species.
虽然这令人悲伤，但研究人员对这具尸体进行了解剖，以获取关于这一物种的新信息。
"From a scientific and conservation point of view, this is huge", Gabe Davies, a Department of Conservation official, said.
新西兰环境保护部官员盖比·戴维斯说："从科学和保护的视角来看，这样做意义重大。"
Some beached whales who don't survive have their skeletons sent to museums, while many others are returned to the water.
一些未能存活的搁浅鲸鱼的骨架会被送往博物馆，而其他许多鲸鱼则会被送回大海。
This ensures the marine environment benefits because whale carcasses give off many nutrients.
这有助于海洋环境，因为鲸鱼尸体能释放出大量营养物质。
"When they fall and die and sink to the bottom of the ocean, they form these little nutrient-rich islands that can support a huge diversity of life", says Dr Brownlow.
布朗洛博士说："当它们倒下死去并沉入海底时，就形成了这些富含营养的小岛屿，能够滋养多种多样的生命。"
The more research that can be done, the better.
能够进行的研究越多越好。
For now, we can only do what we can to keep our oceans clean and safe.
就目前而言，我们只能尽我们所能来保持海洋的清洁和安全。